<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>CalendarProject on Bruce&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/calendarproject/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CalendarProject on Bruce&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.132.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 07:14:28 +1200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/calendarproject/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Git Update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-09-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 07:14:28 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-09-09/</guid>
      <description>Today I have been testing my calendar script. I have not had any issues with excuting the script in google excel. I have removed the following github repos as they are related to my current build
Which was the ticketing system.
Code - 24QCES4YJ09</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appscript Update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 07:15:46 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-29/</guid>
      <description>Project update I have finally fixed the issue with the months. Since my last app script version was counting each date. This time I have utilized JavaScript used its built-in functions.
Also, I have decided to not use an email function as it is making unnecessary work for me and also it&amp;rsquo;s hard to find all the information. I will be updating my idea after I complete the next few functions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appscript update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 15:01:32 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-20/</guid>
      <description>Version Review Today I have been reviewing version 2 of my script. The climbing issue of having to create and keep track of the events while preparing for the week is quite frustrating at the least. My Version 3 is to focus on efficiency and also portability.
Currently, I have created a template sheet that generates calendar events based on the tags.
Two issues I have currently related to these events are the following: At the end of the month of the year, How do I change this?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google App Script Update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 21:58:28 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-13/</guid>
      <description>I have been testing the app scripting since updating the entry. However, I am going as I have been testing, I have been wanting to change the build since the design is more minimalist and also does not clutter the page.
Currently, the design looks like this.
However, I realized that react is very difficult to implement globally. So Alternatively I will remain using the spreadsheet as the base of my tool.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 20:22:28 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-03/</guid>
      <description>Since Coming Back to Arch OS. I have been much more technical. Also, I feel freer because I can modify the system without restrictions. However, with these changes, there will never be without cons. At this stage, the only con I have found is package management. I can not keep track of what is installed on my computer.
In terms of upskilling, I have started updating the following repository.
Link - https://github.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Update Calendar Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-06-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 10:57:53 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-06-30/</guid>
      <description>Link - https://github.com/BruceYoung19/GoogleCalendarScript
Upskilling Log What have I learned:
Data structures Arrays Dates Google scripting Git commit Technical Documentation Should be keeping up with the time frame Git hub License What I could have worked on:
Git fork API Version Control Version 1 - code.gs
only able to make events Problem:
This is not useable on a daily use. Version 2 - Codev2.gs
Spreadsheet to make all the events Creating a tag for the event STRUCTURE = [TAG] Event , startdate, enddate, description, code This can work in a span of a timeframe creating with one line of code.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
